

TA HOANG LONG

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CONTACT

(+65) 9198 7568 (+84) 865872034 tahoanglong2011@gmail.com http://vn.linkedin.com/pub /ta-hoang-

SUMMARY

11+ years of working experience in building software solutions in various business domains, such as banking, real estate, crypto, trading, investment, retail, media. 6 years of working experience in Singapore.

Besides, interested in learning about Data Science and Artificial Intelligence.

Experienced in working for a big corporation, SME, and startup as well.

Have strong background in Computer Science and studied a Master of Business Information System course.

Fluent in communication and good interpersonal skills, able to communicate and work effectively with stack holders and cross-functional team members.

Well-developed analytical thinking, problem solving and product mindset.

Highly motivated self-learner, capable of both team work and individual work.

EDUCATION

long/25/b89/712/

EXPERIENCE

MASTER OF BUSINESS IINFORMATION SYSTEM

Vietnam - Germany University 09/2014

BACHELOR OF PHYSICS AND COMPUTER SCIENCE

University of Science
Ho Chi Minh City
09/2010

HIGHER DIPLOMA OF SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

FPT Aptech 09/2010

SENIOR FULLSTACK DEVELOPER (SINGAPORE)

SINGAPORE GOVERNMENT'S INVESTMENT CORPORATION | 12/2019 - PRESENT Established in 1981 to manage Singapore's foreign reserves, GIC is a global long-term investor with well over US\$100 billion in assets in over 40 countries worldwide.

EISIGHT - Portal for hosting investment research articles and dashboards

- Designed and imlemented a beautiful website with excellent UX for both mobile and desktop devices, helping all GIC staff to search, view and interact with research articles and dashboards, created by investment proffesionals or collected from external partners.
- Designed and fully built a reliable and scalable backend and admin site for storing and managing articles, channels, tags, meta data, interactions, as well as sending daily and adhoc emails to subscribed users.
- Tech-stack: Antd, React, Redux Saga, JWT, .NET Core Web API, Entity Framework Core, SQL Server, Git, Jenkin, Docker.

TECH SKILLS

EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

FRONTEND:

- o HTML
- o CSS
- JAVASCRIPT
- JQUERY
- BOOTSTRAP
- o ANGULAR 2+
- o REACT
- o REDUX SAGA
- o TELERIK
- o KENDO UI
- o ANTD

BACKEND:

- o C#, VB.NET
- .NET FRAMEWORK
- .NET CORE
- ASP.NET WEBFORM
- ASP.NET MVC
- o WEB API
- ENTITY FRAMEWORK
- o REDIS CACHE

DATABASE:

- SQL SERVER
- o ORACLE
- o POSTGRES

METHODOLOGY AND TOOL:

- o GIT
- o TFS
- o SVN
- o UML
- o JENKIN
- o DOCKER
- o SCRUM

SENIOR FULLSTACK DEVELOPER (SINGAPORE)

GLOBAL CRYPTO OFFERING EXCHANGE | 05/2018 - 09/2019

GCOX is the world's first platform that tokenises popularity, helps celebrities create their personal crypto tokens and manage their ITS listing on the platform.

GCOX Know Your Customer (KYC)

- Designed and implemented high-performance backend and APIs for Know Your Customer (KYC) module which enables users to upload identity documents and automatically verify user identity before allowing transactions.
 Integrate the solution with Jumio ID verification platform as a partner.
- Built a convenient admin site for internal staffs to manage end-users' credentials, KYC and Anti Money Laundering (AML) status.
- Tech-stack: .NET Core Web API, Entity Framework Core, PostgresSQL, Github, AWS, ASP.NET Core MVC, OAuth/OpenID, Redis.

GCOX Wallet and DEX App

- Build a user-friendly web and desktop wallet app for token holders to manage accounts and interact with the blockchain, such as create accounts, send/receive funds, trade assets.
- Tech-stack: Angular 7, Electron (for building cross platform desktop apps).

SENIOR ANALYST (SINGAPORE)

AVANADE | 02/2016 - 05/2018

Avanade, founded as a joint venture between Microsoft Corporation and Accenture, is the leading provider of innovative digital and cloud services, business solutions and design-led experiences delivered through the Microsoft technologies.

JTC Real Estate Management System and Customer Service Portal

- JTC Corporation, formerly the Jurong Town Corporation, is the lead agency in Singapore to spearhead the planning, promotion and development of a dynamic industrial landscape.
- Supported, maintained and enhanced the JTC Real Estate Management System, an essential big legacy web application which consists of multiple backend components and several interfaces with internal JTC systems and external government's systems, as well as complex business rules and workflows.
- Designed and built a great new version of JTC Customer Service Portal, a customer facing web application, with modern UI and tech frameworks for better performance and user experience.
- Tech-stack: ASP.NET Webform, MS SQL Server, Telerik control, WCF, K2.

EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

APPLICATION ANALYST (SINGAPORE)

FPT ASIA PACIFIC | 01/2015 - 01/2016

FPT Asia Pacific (FAP) is a subsidiary of FPT Software, the global leading technology and IT services corporation.

Starhub Retail Store Management

- Starhub is the biggest client of FAP in Singapore.
- Maintained and enhanced a system that supports Starhub shops and exclusive partners to manage stocks
 and inventories. Built a robust web application and reliable background processes to collect and process
 inventory data from logistics partners. Developed web APIs to communicate with other internal systems
 such as Starhub Online Store.
- Tech-stack: ASP.NET MVC, Entity Framework, MS SQL Server, KendoUI, Web API.

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER / TEAM LEADER

HARVEY NASH VIETNAM | 07/2013 - 01/2015

Harvey Nash Vietnam (now NashTech) is part of Harvey Nash Group, a pioneer in Headhunting, professional recruitment and IT/BPO outsourcing services, headquaters in London, UK.

Integrated Housing Management System (Civica Housing Cx)

- Joined a big project to build Civica Housing Cx product for Civica, one of the UK's largest software companies. Local authorities, housing associations and registered providers will use Civica Housing Cx as their main line of business application to support the service they deliver to their tenants and customers.
- Delivered high-quality code and provided decent support to team members.
- Tech-stack: ASP.NET MVC, NHibernate, MS SQL Server, KendoUI, NUnit, TFS.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

SACOMBANK | 04/2011 - 07/2013

Sacombank is among top 10 best commercial banks in Vietnam.

Provided high-quality solution development, production support, maintainance and enhancements to various large and small end-user applications (web/windows applications) and background systems that support the banking business processes, such as Data Synchronization System for Internet Banking, National Bank Report Generation System, Fund Management System, Key Performance Index (KPI) System.

Techstack:

- Application development: Microsoft SQL Integration Service (SSIS), .NET, ASP.NET MVC, C#, VB.NET.
- Core-Banking scripting: Temenos T24 JBase.
- Database: SQL Server, Oracle.
- Tools: Visual Studio, HP Load Runner.